内蒙古自治区包头市二零二三年初中学业水平考试。
第一节，听下面五段对话，根据你听到的内容选出相应的图片。
1. Bill, your face looks red.
What's the matter?
I have a fever.
My head feels hot, too.
Bill, your face looks red.
What's the matter?
I have a My head feels hot, too.
2. I'm going out for shopping.
Do you need anything?
Oh, yeah. Can you buy some milk?
I'm going out for shopping.
Do you need anything?
Oh, yeah. Can you buy some milk?
3. Are you a football fan, Jack?
Yes, I go to the stadium whenever there is a good game.
Are you a football fan, Jack?
4. Oh, I can't find my white shoes.
I have to wear them to the sports meeting today.
You always leave things everywhere in the room.
Let me help you.
Oh, I can't find my white shoes.
I have to wear them to the sports meeting today.
You always leave things everywhere in the room.
Let me help you.
5. It's May 24th today.
When will Maria come back from Shanghai?
miss her so much.
She will be back soon.
It's May 24th today.
When will Maria come back from Shanghai?
I miss her so much.
She will be back soon.
听第六段材料，回答第六至八题。
6. David, would you like to help me do the cleaning?
Yes, Grandma. Thank you, dear.
You can tidy up the living room first, and I will clean the kitchen.
Okay, then I will clean the bedroom.
Well, it will take a long time to finish the housework.
If you feel tired, take a break.
Help yourself to some strawberries on the table in the living room.
Alright. David, would you like to help me do the cleaning?
Yes, Grandma. Thank you, dear.
You can tidy up the living room first, and I will clean the kitchen.
Okay, then I will clean the bedroom.
Well, it will take a long time to finish the housework.
If you feel tired, take a break.
Help yourself to some strawberries on the table in the living room.
Alright. And get off at the East Lake Station.
阅读第七段材料，回答第九至十一题。
Then you will see a shopping center on your right.
The museum is next to it.
Take bus number five?
Hmm, I see.
Thanks a lot.
That's alright. Excuse me, how can I get to the science museum?
The science museum?
It's about two kilometers away from here.
It will take you about 30 minutes to walk there.
Can I go there by bus?
Yes, you can take bus number five and get off at the East Lake Station.
Then you will see a shopping center on your right.
The museum is next to it.
Take bus number five?
Hmm, I see.
Thanks a lot.
That's alright. Nice.
听第八段材料，回答第十二。
十四题。
Where are they from?
My coins come from many countries, such as China, Australia, and the UK.
Why do you like collecting coins?
I like the history behind them.
My aunt taught me a lot.
She's an expert in this field.
That's so cool.
Which one is your favorite?
I once saw a with a square hole.
It's from ancient China.
It's amazing. Hi, Jack.
You have a lot of don't you?
Yes, I do.
I have collected 220 coins altogether.
Wow. How long have you spent collecting so many coins?
For about three years.
Nice. Where are they from?
My coins come from many countries, such as China, Australia, and the UK.
Why do you like collecting coins?
I like the history behind them.
My aunt taught me a lot.
She's an expert in this field.
That's so cool.
Which one is your favorite?
I once saw a coin with a square hole.
It's from ancient China.
它太神奇了。
听第九段材料，回答第十五至十七题。
What happened to you?
Why do you look so angry?
I'm angry with my son Leo.
He always spends many hours on the computer, but not enough time on his schoolwork.
Oh dear. And just now, his teacher told me that he failed his exam.
That's too bad.
Why don't you stop him?
I have told him that he shouldn't use the computer during the weekdays, but on
weekends. Can he follow your advice?
No. You are his uncle.
He trusts you most.
Could you have a talk with him about it?
Well, I will have a try.
What happened to you?
Why do you look so angry?
I'm angry with my son Leo.
He always spends many hours on the computer, but not enough time on his schoolwork.
Oh dear. And just now, his teacher told me that he failed his exam.
That's too bad.
Why don't you stop him?
I have told him that he shouldn't use the computer during the weekdays, but on
weekends. Can he follow your advice?
You are his uncle.
He trusts you most.
Could you have a talk with him about it?
Well, I will have a try.
听第十段材料，回答第十八。
二十题。
My name is Emma.
Can you ride a bike well?
It was Friday yesterday, and I had a school trip to a bike museum with my
classmates. We met outside the school library at 7.50 in the morning.
Then, we took the school bus to the museum.
Each ticket cost $5.
We were surprised to see so many bikes.
There were also bike parts, like wheels.
We learned the history of bikes from a guide.
At the end of the trip, we watched a performance of a man riding a bike.
It was amazing.
We were happy to have a trip like this.
My name is Emma.
Can you ride a bike well?
It was Friday yesterday, and I had a school trip to a bike museum with my
classmates. We met outside the school library at 7.50 in the morning.
Then, we took the school bus to the museum.
Each ticket cost $5.
We were surprised to see so many bikes.
There were also bike parts, like wheels.
We learned the history of bikes from a guide.
At the end of the trip, we watched a performance of a man riding a bike.
It was amazing.
We were happy to have a trip like this.